johnlobb.com 2017-06-16

# Privacy policy | John Lobb - Official website

Johnlobb.com privacy policy and protection of personal data - October 2013

JOHN LOBB has created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") in order to communicate its policies and practices relating to the collection, use and disclosure of information obtained on the Johnlobb.com website.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. JOHN LOBB may change or update this Privacy Policy periodically; see "Changes and Updates to Privacy Policy." You can view the most current version of the Privacy Policy at any time by visiting this section or by contacting our [Customer Services Department](http://www.johnlobb.com/contacts).

If you decide to purchase John Lobb products on the Johnlobb.com website, you consent to the collection, the use and the disclosure of your information, including personal and financial information, on the terms described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, or any modifications thereto, please exit the Johnlobb.com website now and do not purchase any of the John Lobb products offered for sale on the website.

## What information is collected on Johnlobb.com?

You may use the Johnlobb.com website without providing any personal information to JOHN LOBB. You will however, need to provide certain information, including:

\- Your e-mail address if you wish to receive such information by JOHN LOBB,

\- Your name, address, telephone number, as well as certain financial information (such as your debit or credit card number) if you choose to purchase products offered on the Johnlobb.com website for the purposes of paying for the products you ordered, the processing of your order and to ensure full completion of any legal, administrative, accounting and/or fiscal requirements linked to your order.

Any information you provide on the Johnlobb.com website may be processed in France and will be stored on John Lobb’s server in France.

Your personal information is kept for ten (10) years in relation to any purchase made, pursuant to the articles of the French “Code de Commerce”. However, your credit and/or debit card information collected in order to facilitate refunds by JOHN LOBB in the event of a withdrawal shall be deleted from our system within fifteen (15) days from delivery to you of your ordered product(s).

In addition, you may at any time request deletion of your personal information by sending an e-mail to JOHN LOBB as soon as your order has been processed and delivered (see "Changes and access to your personal information"). JOHN LOBB may collect non-personal information about you even if you do not purchase any products on the Johnlobb.com website; see "Cookies."

## Receiving information

With your prior and explicit consent only, JOHN LOBB, also provides you with the opportunity to receive information which may be of interest to you, including information relating to JOHN LOBB and new products offered on the Johnlobb.com website. If you do not wish to receive such information by e-mail anymore, you may, at any time, choose not to receive further communications by contacting our Customer Services Department.

## What use is made of the information you provide on Johnlobb.com?

JOHN LOBB may also disclose the information you provide on the Johnlobb.com website to third parties such as service providers who perform services to the Johnlobb.com website. To verify your information, authenticate payments and process orders, JOHN LOBB may disclose certain financial and other information you provide to JOHN LOBB to third parties that provide credit reporting, payment or order fulfillment services.

JOHN LOBB may disclose your information if we reasonably believe that such disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable laws, a subpoena or other legal process. For example, JOHN LOBB may disclose such information as is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against a person or entity who may be violating the Johnlobb.com Terms and Conditions, or who may be causing injury to, or interfering with, other users of the Johnlobb.com website. In the event that JOHN LOBB or all or part of its or their assets, are acquired by a third party, the Johnlobb.com customer list may be included in the transferred assets.

Please be aware that JOHNLOBB will use all reasonable efforts to ensure the safeguarding, security and confidentiality of all collected personal information on such transfers. 

## Cookies

JOHN LOBB reserves the right to use cookies and similar devices strictly necessary to facilitate your navigation and performance on the Johnlobb.com website and to customize the information that appears on the website. JOHN LOBB collects this information in order to monitor usage of the Johnlobb.com website and to improve aspects of the website.

Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but can also be configured not to do so or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you disable your browser from accepting cookies, it will prevent you from moving freely from page to page and from taking full advantage of all of the features of the Johnlobb.com website.

## Links

The Johnlobb.com website may contain links to other third party websites. JOHN LOBB has no control over the content, policies or actions of these websites. The use of any information you may provide to third parties on other websites, or which such parties may otherwise collect on other websites, is not governed by this Privacy Policy and Protection of Personal Data. You should carefully review the privacy policies and protection of personal data of any third party websites and contact the operators of those websites if you have any questions about their use of your information. JOHN LOBB shall not be responsible for any third party, its affiliates or agents, for failing to use your personal information in accordance with such third party's privacy policy and/or practices, or any contractual or other legal obligations to which such third party, its affiliates or agents, may be subject to.

## Security

JOHN LOBB has implemented security measures to protect your personal information you provide to us against unauthorized access and use. All financial information you provide on the Johnlobb.com website is stored on a secure site operated by JOHN LOBB’s financial institution. Transactions conducted on the Johnlobb.com website are protected by an SSL encrypting system. Please be aware, however, that no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure and any information disclosed online can potentially be collected and used by persons other than the intended recipient.

## Changes and updates to Privacy Policy

By using the Johnlobb.com website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy reflects the John Lobb current business practices, and is subject to changes and updates. In the event of any changes or updates, a revised policy will be posted online on the Johnlobb.com website, with the last date of update noted on the bottom of the page. Please check the Johnlobb.com website periodically to remain informed of any changes or updates to the JOHN LOBB’s privacy policies and practices. If you allow JOHN LOBB to retain your personal information you provide to us on the Johnlobb.com website in its customer database and JOHN LOBB intends to disclose that information to third parties or affiliates in a manner that is not already outlined in this Privacy Policy, JOHN LOBB will notify you as soon as possible by e-mail and provide you with an opportunity to refuse any further use or disclosure of your personal information.

## Changes and access to your personal information

You may at any time, ask JOHN LOBB for access to or to correct, update or delete information you have provided to JOHN LOBB for customer database of Johnlobb.com, by contacting our [Customer Services Department](http://www.johnlobb.com/contacts). If applicable, you should ensure to provide JOHN LOBB with any updates and changes to your personal information, including any changes to your postal or e-mail address as to ensure that your orders are shipped to the correct address and to enable us to contact you about your order if necessary. JOHN LOBB may also retain, for archival purposes, copies of communications with users of the Johnlobb.com website and any response to questions or comments sent to users by our [Customer Services Department](http://www.johnlobb.com/contacts).

## Contact us

If you have any questions or comments about the JOHN LOBB privacy policies and practices, please feel free to contact our [Customer Services Department](http://www.johnlobb.com/contacts) by e-mail.
